<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><atom:link rel="hub" href="http://tumblr.superfeedr.com/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"/><description>A multidisciplinary research institute dedicated to advancing knowledge about culture, philosophy, history, and the arts.</description><title>Stanford Humanities Center</title><generator>Tumblr (3.0; @stanfordhumanitiescenter)</generator><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/</link><item><title>Remembering Graham Leggat (1960-2011)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;by Marie-Pierre Ulloa, Stanford Humanities Center&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham Leggat, Stanford alumnus and former executive director of the San Francisco Film Society, transformed the Bay Area film scene. Tobias Wolff, the Ward W. and Priscilla B. Woods Professor of English at Stanford, remembers him with “immense fondness and admiration” as “one of the most interesting students I had.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Visionary executive director of the San Francisco Film Society, Graham Leggat, class of ‘87, died on August 25th at his home in San Francisco after an eighteen-month struggle with cancer. He was 51.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Leggat collaborated frequently with various Stanford institutions to bring foreign films to campus. I had the pleasure of working with Leggat on four different occasions, first, on behalf of the Mediterranean Studies Forum and then for the Humanities Center.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Leggat became the executive director of the San Francisco Film Society in October 2005 after two decades in the non-profit arts world where he held executive positions at the American Museum of Moving Image, the Museum of Modern Art, and the Film Society of Lincoln Center in New York City.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“For nearly six exciting and transformative years, Graham Leggat led the San Francisco Film Society with irrepressible determination, dash and design,” wrote Pat McBaine, president of the Film Society’s board of directors. “His vision, leadership, passion, work ethic, tenacity, imagination and daring along with his colorful language and wicked Scottish sense of humor have indelibly marked our organization with a valuable legacy and left it in the best shape - artistically, organizationally and financially - in its 54-year history.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Quest for Enlightenment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leggat was born in England in 1960, of Scottish parents. He came to Stanford in 1979 on a soccer scholarship. Commenting on his athletic gifts he once joked, “Dad was a professional soccer player, so I had a genetic advantage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On his journey of “looking for enlightenment,” he spent eight years earning his B.A. in modern English and American literature and American studies at Stanford. This extended period of study was, to paraphrase Thoreau, because he “loved a broad margin to his life” and spent three of those years studying Zen in the monastic setting of Tassajara, the San Francisco Zen Center.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;During his tenure at Stanford, he was the editor of the campus literary magazine, and earned a $1,000 prize for being named outstanding undergraduate-in-the-creative-arts. Graham Leggat then went on to earn his M.A. at Syracuse University where he studied fiction writing with acclaimed author Tobias Wolff, who would later join the Stanford English Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing a Love of Film&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leggat’s collaboration with Stanford began in 2007 when, as the Associate Director for &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stanford.edu/group/mediterranean/home/index.html"&gt;Mediterranean Studies&lt;/a&gt;, I worked with him to organize a screening of the acclaimed Algerian film, &lt;em&gt;Rome Rather Than You&lt;/em&gt; in Palo Alto. After the screening, students and community members joined in a discussion with Tariq Teguia, the film’s director. In 2008, Mediterranean Studies co-sponsored a SF Film Festival presentation of the Greek movie, &lt;em&gt;Valse Sentimentale&lt;/em&gt;, directed by another young and daring Mediterranean filmmaker, Constantina Voulgaris.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The same year, Graham and his team facilitated a showing of the Venice Film Festival award winner, &lt;em&gt;The Secret of the Grain&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Tunisian-French filmmaker Abdellatif Kechiche. Screened at the Cubberley Auditorium at Stanford, the event was well attended by students and sparked a lively discussion afterwards with film studies professor &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://art.stanford.edu/profile/Pavle+Levi/"&gt;Pavle Levi&lt;/a&gt;. Students’ eyes were opened to the complexities of the Muslim migrant experience in southern Europe through the vision of a film director with a uniquely provocative storytelling style.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our last collaboration took place in April, 2011 when renowned &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://shc.stanford.edu/news-announcements/video-podcasts/detail/cinema-catharsis"&gt;French film critic Jean-Michel Frodon&lt;/a&gt; was the 2011 Bliss Carnochan Visitor at the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://shc.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford Humanities Center&lt;/a&gt;. Together, Leggat and I arranged to have Frodon participate in the SF Film Festival during his time at Stanford. Leggat invited Frodon to give the master class in film criticism for the 54th San Francisco International Film Festival (see &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/14343937"&gt;video of the SFIFF54 Master Class: Critic’s Response and Responsibility with Jean-Michel Frodon&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Working with Graham was pure joy. He truly cared about including Stanford, his alma mater, in the life of the festival and the film society. He firmly believed in the inspirational and transformative values of films, and in educating the students in the art of cinema. It says a lot that in 2009 he hired the highly-talented Rachel Rosen, a Stanford’s alumna who earned her M.A in Documentary Film in 1993, to be the director of programming for the film society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remembering a Visionary in the Arts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Remembering Graham is remembering his charismatic presence, his talent in mentoring a “crack team” of collaborators, his clean cut elegance, his gracious way of being in the world, his commitment to the civic and cultural missions of film festivals, his humorous irreverence, delivered in one-liners with his “je ne sais quoi” of an accent, his amazing talent of making you feel that you are the most important person in the room.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Remembering him is remembering fun conversations about French cinema  - “a true cinephile is a cinephile of French films” he’d say, knowing how the French love to bask in those kinds of compliments!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Remembering Graham Leggat is also remembering his legacy. He boldly (and baldly) took the San Francisco Film Society where no one had taken it before. He gave film lovers in the Bay Area permission to believe that San Francisco can be both an international and local “futurist” destination. He and his team brought star power to the festival, such as bay area icons George Lucas, Francis Ford Coppola, Sean Penn, Robert Redford but also international artists Tilda Swinton, Walter Salles, Ewan McGregor, Werner Herzog, Mike Leigh.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Under his charismatic leadership, the Film Society extended his programming to being on a daily, year-round basis; the Society offers a magnificent autumnal season of seven festivals: Hong Kong Cinema, Taiwan Film Days, the NY/SF International Children’s Film Festival, French Cinema Now, Cinema by the Bay, the San Francisco International Animation Festival and New Italian Cinema.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Last but not least, Leggat’s legacy will shine through the San Francisco Film Society’s New People Cinema, which will open its doors on September 1st, in a remarkable, state-of-the art theater in Japantown.  This new theater will enable the Film Society to make a daily impact on the cultural life of the community it serves, a realization of Leggat’s ultimate ambition.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Graham Leggat is the author of a science fiction novel, &lt;em&gt;Song of a Dangerous Paradise&lt;/em&gt;, published in 2007 (Cambrian Press). He is also Chevalier de l’Ordre des Arts et des Lettres de la Republique Francaise, in recognition of his outstanding contribution to cinema.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Leggat is survived by his parents Graham and Marilyn of Niagara Falls, Canada, son William and daughters Vhary and Isabelle, sister Alexandra Leggat of Toronto, partner Diana Chiawen Lee, former wife Ellen Hughes, mother of his daughters and former wife Lillian Heard, mother of his son.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In lieu of flowers, donations in Leggat’s memory may be made to the San Francisco Film Society. Condolences should be sent to inmemoryofgraham@sffs.org or c/o Jessica Anthony, SFFS, 39 Mesa Street, Suite 110, The Presidio, San Francisco, CA 94129.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A memorial service, open to the public, is planned for late September. For information visit: &lt;a href="http://sffs.org/"&gt;http://sffs.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9928923681</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9928923681</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 13:46:01 -0700</pubDate></item><item><title>2012-13 Fellowship Applications Now Open</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The Stanford Humanities Center is now accepting fellowship applications for the 2012-13 academic year.  &lt;span&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://shc.stanford.edu/fellowships/non-stanford-faculty"&gt;External Faculty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and a new &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://shc.stanford.edu/fellowships/arts"&gt;Arts Writer/Practitioner fellowship&lt;/a&gt; have a deadline of October 3, 2011.  &lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/fellowships/stanford-faculty"&gt;Stanford Faculty&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/fellowships/stanford-students/graduate"&gt;Dissertation Fellows&lt;/a&gt; have a deadline of January 11, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://shc.onlineapplicationportal.com/"&gt;online application portal&lt;/a&gt; is now available.  For more information, contact Fellowship Program Administrator &lt;a href="mailto:rbarrick@stanford.edu"&gt;Robert Barrick&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564242728</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564242728</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 16:41:00 -0700</pubDate><category>Fellows News</category></item><item><title>2010-11 Fellow Richard White Featured on NPR-Morning Edition</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2010-11 Donald Andrews Whittier Fellow &lt;span&gt;Richard White&lt;/span&gt; was featured on NPR’s &lt;em&gt;Morning Edition&lt;/em&gt; on July 11, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White discussed his new book &lt;em&gt;Railroaded: The Transcontinentals and the Making of Modern America&lt;/em&gt; as the first in a three-part series on 19th Century events that shape the America we live in today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a title="NPR Morning Edition" href="http://www.npr.org/2011/07/11/137497772/how-trains-railroaded-the-american-economy"&gt;Listen to the story.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9141759690</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9141759690</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 16:41:00 -0700</pubDate><category>Fellows News</category></item><item><title>Call for Nominations for 2012-13 International Visitors</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nomination Deadline: November 1, 2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Humanities Center and the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies (FSI) intend to offer up to four short-term residencies to international scholars in academic year 2012-2013. Residencies will be approximately four weeks. Depending on the availability of funds, longer visits of up to eight weeks may be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the fourth year of the program; the list of 2011-2012 visiting scholars is available at: &lt;a title="http://shc.stanford.edu/people/visiting-scholars?fellowship-year=2010-2011" href="http://shc.stanford.edu/people/visiting-scholars?fellowship-year=2010-2011"&gt;&lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/people/visiting-scholars?fellowship-year=2010-2011"&gt;http://shc.stanford.edu/people/visiting-scholars?fellowship-year=2010-2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the residencies is to bring next generation leading scholars into the intellectual life of Stanford, targeting those scholars who would be of particular interest to departments and other units on campus and who fit within the respective missions of the Humanities Center and FSI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International scholars in residence will be given shared-office space at the Humanities Center and be invited to weekday lunches with the Humanities Center fellows. They will also participate in a research group at one of the FSI centers. They will receive a stipend of $2,000 per week for the duration of their visit plus a housing and cost of living allowance of up to $3,000. The Humanities Center and FSI will cover travel expenses (economy class) for one round trip from their place of origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford departments, programs, and research centers and institutes are each eligible to nominate one candidate for consideration for a residency in 2012-2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details on the nomination process are below. Nominating units are asked to commit to hosting at least one activity with the candidate, should the nomination be successful. Examples of such activities include: student workshops, faculty discussion sessions, departmental lectures, participation in departmental colloquia, etc. Note that these visitors may not offer courses for credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selections will be made by a committee convened by the Humanities Center and FSI. Especially appropriate are candidates who are finishing a project and are in a position to share the results with colleagues on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eligibility and Nomination Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford University departments, programs and research centers are each eligible to nominate one candidate through their chair or director. Preference will be given to departments, programs and research centers that have not recently hosted a FSI/Humanities Center visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominations should include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brief rationale for nomination, including a précis of the candidate’s profile and an explanation of how the candidate would fit with the respective missions of the Humanities Center and FSI and engage collegially with the intellectual communities of the institutes (approx. 500 words: see&lt;a title="http://shc.stanford.edu" href="http://shc.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu"&gt;http://shc.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="http://fsi.stanford.edu" href="http://fsi.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fsi.stanford.edu"&gt;http://fsi.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for more information about the two institutes).  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A commitment from the nominating unit to host at least one activity with the candidate if she or he is selected, along with a brief proposal for a possible activity (one to two sentences).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indication from one of FSI’s research centers or programs that the candidate would be of interest to their community. (For the list of FSI’s research centers, and programs, see &lt;a title="http://fsi.stanford.edu/centers/" href="http://fsi.stanford.edu/centers/"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fsi.stanford.edu/centers/"&gt;http://fsi.stanford.edu/centers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Candidate’s CV. Candidates will normally be scholars affiliated with a non- U.S. university or research institution. Candidates must be non-U.S. nationals working abroad. Candidates are expected to be able to function in an English-speaking academic context, although at the department’s discretion, their departmental activity may be conducted in another language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline: Nominations must be submitted by November 1, 2011.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions: Please direct all questions to &lt;a href="mailto:mpulloa@stanford.edu"&gt;Marie-Pierre Ulloa&lt;/a&gt;, the Executive Officer for International Programs, Stanford Humanities Center.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9141931987</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9141931987</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>International News</category></item><item><title>Undergraduate Research</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;By Armine Pilikan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqrj9j3Ju91qmvxz1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research within the humanities can seem like a daunting task. We’re used to short quarter sessions, where terms and dates fly by in a conceptual whirlwind of midterms and profoundly caffeinated essay writing. In our classes, we might spend one week analyzing a book, two weeks on a social phenomenon, three on an entire epoch. So, how do we escape the curse of the cursory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Humanities Center, an intellectual haven stocked with visiting and on-campus professors, international artists, graduate students, researchers and, most importantly, delightful lunches, provides undergraduates with all of the resources and scholarly Sensei they need for an in-depth research project. Four undergraduate students, coming from any and all disciplines, spend an entire year at the Center developing a single topic with one of the Center’s annual fellows, academic giants in their fields (from a pool of 250 applicants, 6 are awarded fellowships). So, yeah, it’s a little intimidating. But that’s to be expected when you travel deep into the complexities of an intellectual movement, when you look a concept squarely in the face and decide it needs some reconstructive surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Center: A Bubble Within a Bubble&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the students have exclusive researching tools and the fellows’ sharp wits to guide them. Fellows at the Center, external faculty with fresh, outsider perspectives, spend the year working on a specialized focus, with students taking on a subset and making it their own. Students build unique, symbiotic relationships with their advisors: they help fellows further their research, by reading assigned materials and pitching new ideas, and the fellows help them engineer independent projects. They also get paid—$1400 per quarter, for 10 hours a week. To conclude the experience, the students present their work during one of the Center’s weekly show-off-your-research lunch meetings. These presentations, called the Undergraduate Symposium, took place at the Center on May 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These luncheons are miniature academic ventures in themselves. Professors, students, and artists come together to chat over Indian food and brownie squares. Harley Adams, an undergraduate fellow researching the colonial archives of the Indian Ocean with Giorgio Riello, loves being brought into these conversations. “At this one lunch table you have guys that are doing global history from so many different perspectives, Giorgio is working on cotton, someone else is working on Chinese history, or Greek instruction manuals, and they all have different ideas about how history should best be done,” said Adams. Alongside conversational companions, the Center provides a beautiful, reclusive area for studying, its courtyard sprinkled with whimsical plant-life and burbling fountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Wonderful Alternative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project provides firm grounds for research, without one having to commit to an Honors Thesis. “I ended up not doing an Honors Thesis, because I’m double majoring, so this is my way of doing a mini-thesis,” said Richard Sajor, majoring in English and Archeology, who’s currently researching the perception of death in Medieval London alongside faculty fellow Amy Appleford. Sajor was itching for the exposure: “So I’m somebody who has taken all the Medieval courses that I could take…this filled in a lot of places where I felt like there weren’t enough classes,” said Sajor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the Center is the only place you can turn to. For Elizabeth Rasmussen, a junior focusing on Latin American Studies, the Center’s an academic jackpot. Cecilia Mendez, a fellow investigating civil wars in 19th century Peru, offers a wealth of knowledge about Latin American political trends and social customs. “At Stanford, I would not have learned anything about this time period ever.” Furthermore, she does all her reading and writing in Spanish, and she and Mendez always communicate in Spanish. Having taken all possible language courses, this was her one chance to master the foreign tongue. She has been writing profiles on key guerilla leaders in Peru, “organizing them in a more concrete fashion that really hasn’t been done before,” said Rasmussen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carving Academic Pathways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, the applicant may have only vague inklings of what they’re interested in, which, turns out, is totally fine. Elias Rodriquez, a sophomore undertaking his first research project, entered into it thinking, “Yeah, the mind is kind of cool and I like this book…I didn’t really know what I was doing.” But the guidance of his fellow, Heather Love, led him to a thesis on the transience of identity in Virginia Woolf’s The Waves, which relates to her topic, the power of group stigmatization. “She recognized what I was interested and pushed me in certain directions,” said Rodriquez. “Now, I feel like a lot of questions she asks are the questions I ask about all my other papers, basically anything I’m really interested in. She helped me figure out a method of better intellectual engagement, just by virtue of interacting with her.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students meet with their fellow every week, simply to bounce ideas off each other and clarify their goals. For Sajor, sometimes when he mentions a certain idea to Appleford, “all of a sudden she gets a spark and I’ll have 50 million books piled up on my desk the next week that I have to pore through. It’s just awesome to have someone who knows everything about what I want to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources? Yes please.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fellows got connections. The external faculty, coming in from top universities nationwide, provide students with off-campus and eye-opening resources. Sajor, who needed to do tons of manuscript reading, got most of his information from Appleford. “She was able to hook me up with resources from where she works and that was really helpful as well…she’s from the East Coast and that’s where all the manuscripts are,” said Sajor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harley Adams has been working on a quantitative spreadsheet of every factory and every node in the Indian Ocean from 1500-1800, so as to view the exchange of commodities within a more globalized trading structure. Under Riello’s tutelage, Adams was able to work with the Spatial History Lab to digitally render this information on an interactive map, which shows geographic and chronological changes. “What’s interesting is that this information has never been collected in such a way before, centered in one place…it is an important, new way to view history,” said Adams. The course of his voyage has led him to believe that “through just looking at the Indian Ocean, you can see the entire world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That Personal Touch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These guys get to do some pretty cool things. Beyond that, they get to work with mentors who are as relatable as they are brilliant. Adams, who found his sole-interest-mate in Riello, says that together they “look at and admire pictures of Dutch vessels, or 17th century drawings of Canton ports, so we get to mutually admire and engage in art from the field.” Rasmussen and Mendez always start of their meetings with the latest in South American politics, always in Spanish. Sajor and Appleford commiserate and procrastinate together. Love and Rodriquez, always gushing over the same authors, were literarily meant for each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the fellows are not just resources to cling to now—they serve as a lens into the future. Adams states, “Right now, I feel like I know nothing, and then I look at someone like Riello who knows so much and can speak and touch on any subject…So as well as giving me actual quantifiable help, it’s also an inspiration to know that if you work on something, you can get to a level where it really is rewarding, and you can really understand history in a much deeper way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View the Stanford Daily article here: &lt;a title="http://www.stanforddaily.com/2011/06/02/honing-in-on-the-humanities/" href="http://www.stanforddaily.com/2011/06/02/honing-in-on-the-humanities/"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stanforddaily.com/2011/06/02/honing-in-on-the-humanities/"&gt;http://www.stanforddaily.com/2011/06/02/honing-in-on-the-humanities/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email the Fellowship Program Manager at &lt;a href="mailto:rbarrick@stanford.edu"&gt;rbarrick@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; for further information&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9565975637</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9565975637</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><title>Humanities Center Funds 16 Workshops for 2011-12</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Humanities Center is pleased to announce that it will fund 16 Theodore and Frances Geballe Workshop Research Workshops for 2011-12. Of the 16 workshops, 6 are new for this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshops cover a broad range of topics, including “Verbal and Visual Literacies of Ancient Rome,” “Cognition &amp; Language,” and “Visualizing Complexity and Uncertainty,” which focuses on the digital humanities. Chosen by an interdisciplinary Stanford faculty committee, the workshops aim to bring together faculty members and graduate students in cross-disciplinary dialogue. Many workshop meetings are open to the public and will be posted on the &lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/events/calendar/all-events"&gt;calendar &lt;/a&gt;as soon as information is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/workshops/current-workshops"&gt;View the workshops for 2011-12.&lt;/a&gt; Formal descriptions and faculty and graduate student coordinator information will be posted mid-July, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564313755</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564313755</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate><category>workshops</category></item><item><title>Jean-Michel Frodon on the New Frontiers of Film Criticsm</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by Armine Pilikian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqrj2b5eUT1qmvxz1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, the Stanford Humanities Center welcomed Jean-Michel Frodon as its international Bliss Carnochan Visitor. Frodon is one of the most well-known film critics in the world, and surely the most notable in France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Man of Many Charming Hats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born Jean-Michel Billard, Frodon chose his pseudonym (a pre-trilogy-release tribute to J.R.R Tolkien’s novel “The Lord of the Rings”) not from any particular identification with the power-hungry, hairy-footed hobbit, but, first of all to distinguish himself from his father, Pierre Billard, a prominent film critic in France, and, secondly because of his genuine love for the stories. Frodon actually possesses more of a Gandalf-esque aura, sporting a scruffy silvery beard and radiating phenomenal wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As former editor-in-chief of Cahiers du Cinema, the preeminent journal of film criticism in France, Frodon has helped define the role of film and film criticism in society. He has been a fascinating presence in the world of cinema for much of his life, starting his career as a critic for the French weekly Le Point in 1983, moving onto the leading French daily Le Monde in 1990, and then joining Cahiers du Cinema in 2003. He currently works for Slate, where he runs the film criticism blog “Projection Publique.” And like any influential public persona, he maintains an active and tasteful Twitter account.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frodon shares his knowledge in a manner effortlessly fluid, spouting aperçus as if a fountain of cinematic references. This openness reflects his overall approach to film criticism: films, and the resulting impressions and theories, should open up a welcoming space of aesthetic and cultural appreciation for all audiences. And so long as movies continue to tell regenerative stories, evolving to reflect social transmutations cutting deep into our psyches, we will continue to watch and listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Spellbinding Presence on Stanford Campus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During his stay, Jean-Michel Frodon interacted directly with students in two separate on-campus events. One of these events was an illuminating Q&amp;A session with a class spearheading the new student-run Stanford Arts Review, where he provided a shrewd run down of dos and don’ts for online criticism. Frodon also gave a lecture at a Structured Liberal Education (SLE) event, discussing his philosophical views on film’s role in society: past, present, and future. To top it all off, Frodon taught a master class during the San Francisco International Film Festival entitled “The Critic’s Response and Responsibility.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Role of the Critic: Recognizing the Ethics of Aesthetics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Frodon, the images we see on screen change how we see the people in our lives. In every cinematic journey, a relationship builds between the viewers and the oversized people on screen, whether it’s bred of opposition or admiration, of power or submission, of sympathy or disgust. We develop our sense of empathy because we immediately relate to each scene, each interaction. Before we know it, the characters in the story transform into actual individuals, bridging that troublesome gap between non-fiction and fiction: “they are real human beings, and this always brings up something more,” said Frodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, watching a movie isn’t just a nice way to spend Saturday night—it’s a mind-opening experience. “It is a part of this idea, this larger idea that art is this object that is constantly opening these questions: who we are, where we go, how do we relate to others, to friends, children, neighbors…and these issues are constantly brought to light, not finished,” said Frodon. And so it is the critic’s job to zero in on these issues, inventing new insights after each reel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same Purpose, New Venue: Film Criticism in the Digital Age&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During his Stanford Arts Review class Q&amp;A session, Frodon explained the need for the critic’s presence, particularly in the increasingly relevant virtual realm. Frodon certainly practices what he preaches. In June 2001, he initiated an e-version of Cahiers du Cinema. His reasoning: “it’s a huge new market of course, but it’s also the possibility of making an original and exacting voice heard, based on the love of cinema.” If you love something, you have to let it grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, as Frodon states, the “critic is an artist that directly interacts with society,” then digital media is a necessary, and surprisingly creative, tool for the artist-critic. Creative composition kicks in because now we get to hear and see the critic’s ideas: “What we can do now is mix writing with images, sound, hypertext links, to promote circulation and navigation,” said Frodon in the class. Modern critics are at liberty to layer their words with a host of vibrant stimuli, stirring new associations and emotional responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Hutchins, the Stanford Arts Review class instructor, said after his visit, “Frodon really emphasized the importance of making the magazine speak to the audience, always being wary of becoming a magazine that speaks to itself.” Communicating with an audience takes conscious effort on the part of the source, and for Frodon, it is an effort crucial to the persistence of art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Film, Alive and Well&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although many argue that film, along with other art forms, needs to be put on life-support and fast, Frodon argued for the vitality of cinema at a SLE lecture, which was a part of a cultural series the program holds every Thursday night. One of the students, Vanessa Moody, felt comforted by his perspective: “He had a really optimistic view of film, in terms of the digital realm, in not seeing film as a dying art, but rather as it being reborn in different ways.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frodon believes movies are fueled by this eternal, restless human need—“the need of storytelling.” With each work, the filmmaker announces: “I’m going to tell you a story, and you’re going to listen to my story.” And, despite modern conveniences, we go out of our ways to hear those stories, “we go, all of us, out of our home, into the cold… we have to be in the car, in traffic jams, in the train, but we go to theatres and we keep doing it.” So this love of movies, of storytelling and listening, will never subside. “It is not something that can be reduced. My opinion is that we are absolutely not ready to abandon this relationship,” said Frodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to keep this relationship going steady, some things have to change. Frodon fights against the belief that cinema is dying, that the moving image is accelerating towards a cultural cul-de-sac. He must even struggle with those who truly love film, because they “love cinema so much they will not acknowledge that to keep cinema, for it to remain alive, it has to evolve deeply.” So long as filmmakers continue to adapt, to tell engaging stories in fresh forms, they’ll continue to enchant audiences virtually everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9566024799</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9566024799</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>Arts News</category></item><item><title>Humanities Center to Pilot a Dissertation Writing Group in 2011-12</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Humanities Center is seeking graduate students to join a pilot program of a dissertation writing group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program is meant to foster intensive and supportive exchange across humanistic fields for those in the final stages of dissertation writing. Graduate students from a variety of humanities departments will be able to present and discuss their work in a multidisciplinary context, and faculty fellows in residence at the Humanities Center will participate in workshop meetings as mentors in their areas of expertise. Students whose projects cut across a number of fields may find this forum especially helpful to their scholarship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eligibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford graduate students from humanities departments who have advanced to the chapter-writing phase of the dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meetings will be held in the Baker Room of the Humanities Center from 4 to 6 pm on Thursdays &lt;em&gt;every other week&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eligible students may sign up to participate during &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; of three quarters (autumn, winter, or spring).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must agree to attend all meetings held during that quarter (5 meetings total).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation will be limited to a maximum of 10 students per quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Format&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to two participants will pre-circulate a chapter or portion of a chapter (no more than 35 pages) by Friday of the week preceding each meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group will read these chapters in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each chapter will receive approximately 45 minutes of structured feedback and constructive critique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short portion of each meeting will be devoted to general concerns of the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guests&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants may invite advisors, committee members, and other interested parties to read pre-circulated chapters and attend the meeting at which they present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facilitation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Associate Director of the Humanities Center will run the workshop. Since this is a pilot program, the facilitator will adjust the format to the needs of the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refreshments will be provided in abundance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.stanford.edu/dept/SHC/workshops/dissertationwritinggroup.fb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline is June 6, 2011.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions? Contact &lt;a href="mailto:zelljadt@stanford.edu"&gt;Katja Zelljadt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Resources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stanford.edu/dept/undergrad/cgi-bin/drupal_pwr/hwc_graduates"&gt;Hume Writing Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564405387</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564405387</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 13:30:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><title>International Scholars in Residence at the Humanities Center 2011-12</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Humanities Center and the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies (FSI) are pleased to announce that six international scholars have been chosen to come to Stanford in 2011-12 as part of a jointly sponsored international program entering its third year. Nominated by Stanford departments and research centers, the international scholars will be on campus for four-week residencies. They will have offices at the Humanities Center and will be affiliated with their nominating unit, the Humanities Center, and FSI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major purpose of the residencies is to bring high-profile international scholars into the intellectual life of the university, targeting scholars whose research and writing engage with the missions of both the Humanities Center and FSI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following six scholars have chosen to be in residence during the 2011-2012 academic year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="rteindent1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adams Bodomo&lt;/strong&gt; (October-November 2011) is the Chair of the Department of Linguistics in the School of Humanities at the University of Hong Kong and the Director of the University’s African Studies Program. A linguist hailing from Ghana, his primary expertise resides in the structure of West-African languages (Akan, Dagaare). He has recently undertaken research on the African diaspora in Asia, as well as conducted fieldwork on Zhuang, a minority language in China. He was nominated by the Department of Linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="rteindent1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mario Carretero&lt;/strong&gt; (January 2012) is a Professor of Psychology at Autonoma University of Madrid, and one of the most prominent leaders studying how young people develop historical consciousness and how they understand history. His work has been at the forefront of the “history wars” since the 1990s over what and who should determine the curriculum on the Spanish-speaking world. Carretero’s research, unlike scholars who explore such issues by dissecting textbooks, is unique in its commitment to fieldwork - conducting interviews with adolescents and observing them in real life situations to understand the dynamics of cultural transmission and resistance. He was nominated by the School of Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="rteindent1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catherine Gousseff &lt;/strong&gt;(February 2012) is a world-renowned leading figure in East-Central European history, politics and society of the twentieth Century, as well as of the former Soviet Union. A researcher at the French CNRS (Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique) she is currently affiliated with the Marc Bloch Center in Berlin. While at Stanford, she will share insights into her new research project on collective memories of displacements, diaspora politics in wartime and post-war eras, notably the Polish-Ukrainian population exchange (1944-1950). She was nominated by the Europe Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="rteindent1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Laidlaw&lt;/strong&gt; (April 2012) is an anthropologist at Cambridge University. Professor Laidlaw is deeply engaged in fieldwork in Asia, researching the Buddhist ethics of self-cultivation, looking at how the traditional means by which Buddhists practice self-cultivation –asceticism, meditation- are undergoing a massive restructuring. Practices once reserved for male monks are now being adopted by women and laity. James Laidlaw has edited seven books, the two latest ones on the cognitive approaches to religion, exploring them from an ethnographic perspective. He is also an expert on Jainism, a tradition of monastic renunciation like Buddhism that is also the religion of choice of a larger lay population. He was nominated by the Department of Anthropology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="rteindent1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monica Quijada&lt;/strong&gt; (October-November 2011) is a public intellectual and historian of Spain and Latin America at the Consejo Superior de Investigaciones Cientificas (CSIC) in Madrid. Her engagement with the UN in Argentina (working with refugees) and her directorship of the investigation carried out in the late 1990s regarding Nazi activities during the Second World War and in post-war Argentina shows her commitment to the public space. She has written extensively on dictatorship, populism, and war and their effect on the public sphere in Argentina and Spain as well as on the relationship between nineteenth-century Latin American states and their indigenous populations. She was nominated by the History Department and the Center for Latin American Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="rteindent1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Wolfe&lt;/strong&gt; (May-June 2012) is a historian at La Trobe University in Melbourne, Australia. He is a premier historian of settler colonialism, currently working on a comparative transnational history of settler-colonial discourses of race in Australia, Brazil, the United States, and Israel/Palestine. While at Stanford, he will give lectures based on his core work on Australia and also on his forthcoming book Settler Colonialism and the American West, 1865-1904 (Princeton University Press). He was nominated by the Bill Lane Center for the American West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at Stanford, the scholars will offer informal seminars and public lectures and will also be available for consultations with interested faculty and students. For additional information, please contact Marie-Pierre Ulloa,&lt;a href="mailto:mpulloa@stanford.edu"&gt;mpulloa@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564461705</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564461705</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>international news</category></item><item><title>Fellows Update Spring 2011</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the latest updates from current and former fellows! Please take a moment to send us news about appointments, prizes, publications, and any other events you would like to share with your fellow fellows: &lt;a href="http://shc-newsletter@stanford.edu/"&gt;shc-newsletter@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010-11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HARRIS FEINSOD &lt;/strong&gt;will be a College Fellow at Northwestern University next year. Following this postdoc year, he will join Northwestern’s Department of English as an assistant professor, teaching courses on poetry, poetics, and the literature and culture of the Americas in the 20th century. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LORI FLORES &lt;/strong&gt;received a Consortium for Faculty Diversity (CFD) Postdoctoral Fellowship at Bowdoin College and will be teaching courses for the history, Latin American studies, and gender and women’s studies departments for the 2011-2012 academic year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NATALIE PHILLIPS&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(also 2008-09&lt;/strong&gt;) has been appointed assistant professor of 18th-century British literature in the Department of English at Michigan State. Natalie will be staying on board with the research group at Stanford “Culture, Brain, and Learning,”  returning to Stanford three to four times per year to stay up to date with the fMRI project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COURTNEY ROBY &lt;/strong&gt;will join the Department of Classics at Cornell University as assistant professor in fall 2011. While at the Center she defended her dissertation “The Encounter of Knowledge: Technical Ekphrasis between Alexandria and Rome” and will graduate this spring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAMES WOOD &lt;/strong&gt;will be traveling this summer to the Houghton Library to consult the Donald and Mary Hyde Collection of material relating to Samuel Johnson in preparation for the fifth and final chapter of his dissertation-in-progress “Anecdote and Enlightenment, 1700-1800.” The research trip is funded by Stanford’s Fliegelman Archival Research Award.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009-10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MARY KATHERINE CAMPBELL&lt;/strong&gt; received one of the ACLS future faculty postdocs (offers from Berkeley, NYU, PITT, Ohio State, and Cal Tech), but took an assistant professor position at the University of Tennessee instead. These offers were due, she says, in no small part to the Humanities Center.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008-09&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAN ESTEP &lt;/strong&gt;published the essay “Who’s Afraid of Conceptual Art?” in &lt;em&gt;Quodlibetica&lt;/em&gt; (link to &lt;a href="http://www.quodlibetica.com"&gt;www.quodlibetica.com&lt;/a&gt;), Constellation #7, in April 2010, and the catalogue essay “David Lefkowitz, Other Positioning Systems,” in &lt;em&gt;David Lefkowitz&lt;/em&gt; (Rochester Art Center, 2010). She also published “The Southern Land Not Fully Known: Naming Antarctica” in &lt;em&gt;Quodlibetica&lt;/em&gt;, Constellation #10, October 2010, and “Art, Writing, Disciplinarity: The Political Potential of a Mixed Creative Practice” in &lt;em&gt;Quoblibetica&lt;/em&gt;, Constellation #13, April 2011. To access these publications, visit &lt;a href="http://www.quodlibetica.com/author/jestep/"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.quodlibetica.com/author/jestep/"&gt;http://www.quodlibetica.com/author/jestep/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Jan produced the artist publication/map&lt;em&gt; Beneath the surface (of language), Silver Island Mountain Byway, Wendover, Utah, USA&lt;/em&gt;, in four-color offset print. The map, which is available at Printed Matter Inc., New York, NY, &lt;a href="http://www.printedmatter.org"&gt;www.printedmatter.org&lt;/a&gt;, arose from the short research trip Jan took to the Center for Land Use Interpretation’s (CLUI) artist residency in Wendover, Utah, in Spring 2008, while she was at Stanford. It is modeled after the Wittgenstein map, &lt;em&gt;Searching for Ludwig Wittgenstein, Lake Eidsvatnet, Skjolden, Sogn, Norway &lt;/em&gt;(2007), also at available at Printed Matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2010 she designed and edited the collaborative artist book &lt;em&gt;Issue: LAND, Volume Two&lt;/em&gt; in four-color, offset print. The book features fifteen artist projects that explore current environmental and land-use issues, including Jan’s essay “What Does a Sea Squirt Know? Why Art Needs a Brain,” and artist project “Grand Canyon Suicide Map.” Participating artists include Christine Baeumler (USA), Etienne Boulanger (France), The Center for Land Use Interpretation (USA), Song Chao (China), Matthias Einhoff (Germany), Jan Estep (USA), Simon Faithfull (England), Terike Haapoja (Finland), Nance Klehm (USA), KUNSTrePUBLIK (Germany), Laura Corcoran Mahnke (USA), Anna Metcalfe (USA), Daniel Seiple (USA/Germany), Mona Smith (USA), and Rebar (USA)/Works Progress (USA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan also received a Creative Capital/Warhol Foundation Arts Writers Grant for Short Form Writing, December 2009- March 2011. For more information on Jan’s work and publications, visit &lt;a href="http://www.janestep.com/"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.janestep.com"&gt;www.janestep.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006-07&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEG BUTLER&lt;/strong&gt; was awarded an ACLS Fellowship for 2012 to work on her book manuscript, “The King’s Canvas: The Transformation of Ancient Macedon.”  This is based on her dissertation work, a large part of which she completed as a Geballe fellow. Meg is currently an assistant professor (since 2008) at Tulane, where she is in the Department of Classical Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TROY JOLLIMORE&lt;/strong&gt; is publishing a new book of poems titled &lt;em&gt;At Lake Scugog&lt;/em&gt; this month in the Princeton Series of Contemporary Poets. The philosophical monograph that he started writing at the Center, &lt;em&gt;Love’s Vision&lt;/em&gt;, will be published in June, also by Princeton University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHRISTY PICHICHERO &lt;/strong&gt;is currently finishing a postdoctoral fellowship with Stanford’s Introduction to the Humanities Program. She has been appointed assistant professor of 17th and 18th century French studies at George Mason University and is the associate director of the Middlebury’s French School (summer linguistic and cultural immersion program) at the Mills College West Coast campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ERIC PORTER &lt;/strong&gt;published the book he was working on while in residence at the Center, &lt;em&gt;The Problem of the Future World: W. E. B. Du Bois and the Race Concept at Midcentury&lt;/em&gt; (Duke University Press). The book is a compelling reassessment of the later writings of the iconic African American activist and intellectual W. E. B. Du Bois. &lt;em&gt;The Problem of the Future World&lt;/em&gt; shows how Du Bois’s later writings help to address race and racism as protean, global phenomena in the present. Read more: &lt;a href="http://www.dukeupress.edu/Catalog/ViewProduct.php?productid=14746"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dukeupress.edu/Catalog/ViewProduct.php?productid=14746"&gt;http://www.dukeupress.edu/Catalog/ViewProduct.php?productid=14746&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1995-96&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAMES PORTER&lt;/strong&gt; published &lt;em&gt;The Origins of Aesthetic Thought in Ancient Greece: Matter, Sensation, and Experience&lt;/em&gt;with Cambridge University Press in November 2010. The book traces the origins of aesthetic thought and inquiry in their broadest manifestations as they evolved from before Homer down to the fourth century and then into later antiquity, with an emphasis on Greece in its earlier phases. Read more:&lt;a href="http://www.cambridge.org/gb/knowledge/isbn/item2715142/?site_locale=en_GB"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cambridge.org/gb/knowledge/isbn/item2715142/?site_locale=en_GB"&gt;http://www.cambridge.org/gb/knowledge/isbn/item2715142/?site_locale=en_GB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1992-93&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JOHN SEERY &lt;/strong&gt;published &lt;em&gt;A Political Companion to Walt Whitman &lt;/em&gt;(The University Press of Kentucky, 2010), the first full-length exploration of Whitman’s works through the lens of political theory. Read more:&lt;a href="http://www.kentuckypress.com/live/title_detail.php?titleid=2443"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kentuckypress.com/live/title_detail.php?titleid=2443"&gt;http://www.kentuckypress.com/live/title_detail.php?titleid=2443&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011, John published a second book, &lt;em&gt;Too Young to Run? A Proposal for an Age Amendment to the U.S. Constitution, &lt;/em&gt;with Penn State Press. Read about that book at psupress.org: &lt;a href="http://www.psupress.org/books/titles/978-0-271-04853-6.html"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.psupress.org/books/titles/978-0-271-04853-6.html"&gt;http://www.psupress.org/books/titles/978-0-271-04853-6.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1991-92&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAVID HAHN&lt;/strong&gt; has been contracted by Fin Records to release a single. Fin Records, an audiophile label based in Seattle, releases collector’s edition recordings on green translucent vinyl. The recording will be released later in 2011. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David’s 4-movement piece for mandolin and guitar, &lt;em&gt;Passionate Isolation&lt;/em&gt;, has been published by Clear Note Publications. The piece won the 2003 Composition Prize from the Classical Mandolin Society of America. The work joins Concerto Anatolia and W Is For Weasel at Clear Note. You can hear examples of Passionate Isolation at this link: &lt;a href="http://www.clearnote.net/PassionateIsolation.html"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.clearnote.net/PassionateIsolation.html"&gt;http://www.clearnote.net/PassionateIsolation.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David has two new pieces: “The Massacre of Suns,” for solo voice and dedicated to soprano Beth Griffith with text by Emily Dickinson; and “TIC*TAC*TOE,” for mandolin, guitar, and electronic sound, commissioned by the German-based MARE Duo. It is available as a MIDI version here: &lt;a href="http://soundcloud.com/davidhahn/tic-tac-toe"&gt;&lt;a href="http://soundcloud.com/davidhahn/tic-tac-toe"&gt;http://soundcloud.com/davidhahn/tic-tac-toe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to his compositions, David worked as sound designer for a production of &lt;em&gt;The Happy Ones&lt;/em&gt; now playing at Seattle Public Theatre. A re-mix of some sounds used in the play can be found here:&lt;a href="http://soundcloud.com/davidhahn/happy-ones-the-remix"&gt;&lt;a href="http://soundcloud.com/davidhahn/happy-ones-the-remix"&gt;http://soundcloud.com/davidhahn/happy-ones-the-remix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. He also has a new performing ensemble, Concert Imaginaire, which performs his music. David plays electric guitar, Ruthie Dornfeld plays violin, and Jay Kenney plays synthesizer and bass. They are currently auditioning percussionists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1988-89&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAROLYN WILLIAMS &lt;/strong&gt;published&lt;em&gt; Gilbert and Sullivan: Gender, Genre, Parody&lt;/em&gt;, with Columbia University Press in 2011, which recasts our understanding of creativity in the late nineteenth century. Read more:&lt;a href="http://cup.columbia.edu/book/978-0-231-14804-7/gilbert-and-sullivan"&gt;&lt;a href="http://cup.columbia.edu/book/978-0-231-14804-7/gilbert-and-sullivan"&gt;http://cup.columbia.edu/book/978-0-231-14804-7/gilbert-and-sullivan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1986-87&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RENATO ROSALDO &lt;/strong&gt;has a poetry collection that is scheduled to be published this coming July called &lt;em&gt;Diego Luna’s Insider Tips&lt;/em&gt;. Published by Many Mountains Moving, it won the Many Mountains Moving poetry book manuscript contest for 2009.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564505903</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564505903</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>Fellows News</category></item><item><title>Stanford Humanities Center Names 2011-12 Fellows</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Humanities Center has named 26 fellows for the 2011-12 academic year. Chosen from a pool of nearly 400 applicants, the 2011-12 cohort comprises scholars from other institutions, as well as Stanford faculty and advanced Stanford graduate students. Fellows will pursue individual research and writing for the full academic year while contributing to the Stanford community through their participation in workshops, lectures, and courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shahzad Bashir&lt;/strong&gt;, Internal Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Religious Studies, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persianate Pasts: Memory, Narration, and Ideology in the Islamic East, 1400-1600&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Blumenthal-Barby&lt;/strong&gt;, External Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of German Studies, Rice University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Language of Secularization &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luis Cheng-Guajardo&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Philosophy, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Practical Demand of Means-end Rationality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Margaret Cohen&lt;/strong&gt;, Violet Andrews Whittier Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Comparative Literature, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enchanted Depths: Imagining the Ocean in the Era of Underwater Visualization &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Georgia Cowart&lt;/strong&gt;, Marta Sutton Weeks Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Music, Case Western Reserve University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watteau’s Utopias of Music and Theater: Visions of a New France&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Megan Dean&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of History, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neither Empire Nor Nation: Networks of Trade in the Caucasus, 1750-1925&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leah DeVun&lt;/strong&gt;, External Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of History, Rutgers University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter Sex: Hermaphrodites and the Demands of Difference, 1000-1600&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexander Duncan&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Classics, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tragic Ugliness: An Investigation in Genre and Aesthetics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paula Findlen&lt;/strong&gt;, Ellen Andrews Wright Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of History, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;After Leonardo: The Artist as Scientist in Seventeenth-Century Italy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Gilmartin&lt;/strong&gt;, Marta Sutton Weeks Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of History, North Carolina State University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The People’s Sovereignty: Law, Politics, and Elections in the Making of Modern India&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Gowder&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Political Science, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Egalitarian Theory of the Rule of Law&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thomas Hare&lt;/strong&gt;, Marta Sutton Weeks Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Comparative Literature, Princeton University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Performance and Practice in Buddhist Japan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kristen Haring&lt;/strong&gt;, External Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of History, Auburn University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Placing a Call: How Location and Design Facilitated Telephone Communication&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jillian Hess&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of English, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Commonplace Books: Romantic and Victorian Technologies of Extraction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christopher Hom&lt;/strong&gt;, External Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Philosophy, Texas Tech University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hating and Necessity: The Semantics of Racial Epithets&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miyako Inoue&lt;/strong&gt;, Internal Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Anthropology, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making Modern Evidence: Law, Speech, and Recording Technologies in Japanese Courts&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samuel Kahn&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Philosophy, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Establishing a Kantian Pluralism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Martin&lt;/strong&gt;, Donald Andrews Whittier Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Classics, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Religion, Performance, and Aesthetics in Homeric Poetry&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peggy Phelan&lt;/strong&gt;, Violet Andrews Whittier Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Departments of Drama and English, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Literature and Performance: Expressing the Inexpressible &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Janice Ross&lt;/strong&gt;, Internal Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Drama, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Great Rehearsal: Jewish Identity in Russian Ballet &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C. Namwali Serpell&lt;/strong&gt;, External Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of English, University of California, Berkeley&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seven Modes of Uncertainty&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debora Silverman&lt;/strong&gt;, Marta Sutton Weeks Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of History, University of California, Los Angeles&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Art of Darkness: Art Nouveau, “Style Congo,” and the Belgian Royal Museum of Central Africa, Tervuren, 1897-2010&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malcolm Turvey&lt;/strong&gt;, External Faculty Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Film History, Sarah Lawrence College&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Films of Jacques Tati (1907-1982) and Their Place Within the Overlooked Tradition of Comic Modernism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sylvia Yanagisako&lt;/strong&gt;, Ellen Andrews Wright Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Anthropology, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Made in Translation: A Collaborative Ethnography of Italian-Chinese Ventures in Global Fashion&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Yunker&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of Music, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Politics of Identity in East German Music: Ruth Berghaus and Ruth Zechlin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ryan Zurowski&lt;/strong&gt;, Geballe Dissertation Prize Fellow&lt;br/&gt;Department of English, Stanford University&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;To the Gentle Reader: Prefaces and Books in Early Modern England&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*****************************&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Center’s fellowships are made possible by gifts and grants from the following individuals, foundations and Stanford offices: The Esther Hayfer Bloom Estate, Theodore H. and Frances K. Geballe, Mimi and Peter Haas, Marta Sutton Weeks, the Mericos Foundation, the National Endowment for the Humanities, and the offices of the Dean of Research and the Dean of Humanities and Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564555206</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564555206</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>Fellows News</category></item><item><title>International Scholars in Residence 2010-11</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Humanities Center and the &lt;a href="http://fsi.stanford.edu/"&gt;Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies (FSI)&lt;/a&gt; are pleased to announce that four international scholars have been chosen to come to Stanford in 2010-11 as part of a jointly sponsored international program entering its second year. Nominated by Stanford departments and research centers, the international scholars will be on campus for four-week residencies. They will have offices at the Humanities Center and will be affiliated with their nominating unit, the Humanities Center, and FSI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major purpose of the residencies is to bring high-profile international scholars into the intellectual life of the university, targeting scholars whose research and writing engage with the missions of both the Humanities Center and FSI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following four scholars have been selected for the upcoming academic year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anies Baswedan&lt;/strong&gt;, currently President of Paramadina University in Jakarta, is a leading intellectual figure in Indonesia. In 2008, the editors of &lt;em&gt;Foreign Policy&lt;/em&gt; named him one of the world’s “top 100 public intellectuals.” As an advisor to the Indonesian government, he is a leading proponent of democracy and transparency in Indonesia, a creative thinker about Islam and democracy, as well as a charismatic leader in the educational field. He was nominated by the Abbasi Program in Islamic Studies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephane Dudoignon&lt;/strong&gt; is a political scientist/senior research fellow at the École des hautes études en sciences sociales (EHESS) in Paris. He is one of the world’s leading scholars of Muslim politics and societies from the Caucasus to Central Asia. He is the author of pioneering work on Muslim movements, including the historical study of Sufi networks from the Volga River to China, Muslim intellectuals’ debates about gender, and modern Sunni revivalist movements in Eastern Iran. While on campus, he will give lectures on Islam in Eurasia and Iran, among other things. He was nominated by the Center for Russian, East European and Eurasian Studies (CREEES).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mónica Quijada&lt;/strong&gt; is a high-profile public intellectual and historian of Spain and Latin America at the Consejo Superior de Investigaciones Científicas (CSIC) in Madrid. Her engagement with the UN in Argentina (working with refugees) and her directorship of the investigation carried out in the late 1990s regarding Nazi activities during the Second World War and in post-war Argentina shows her commitment to the public space. She has written extensively on dictatorship, populism, and war and their effect on the public sphere in Argentina and Spain as well as on the relationship between nineteenth-century Latin American states and their indigenous populations. She was nominated by the History Department and the Center for Latin American Studies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Wolfe&lt;/strong&gt; is a historian at La Trobe University in Melbourne, Australia. He is a premier historian of settler colonialism, currently working on a comparative transnational history of settler-colonial discourses of race in Australia, Brazil, the United States, and Israel/Palestine. While at Stanford, he will give lectures based on his core work on Australia and also on his forthcoming book &lt;em&gt;Settler Colonialism and the American West, 1865-1904&lt;/em&gt;(Princeton University Press). He was nominated by the Bill Lane Center for the American West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at Stanford, the scholars will offer informal seminars and public lectures and will also be available for consultations with interested faculty and students. For additional information, please contact &lt;a href="mailto:mpulloa@stanford.edu"&gt;Marie-Pierre Ulloa&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="mailto:mpulloa@stanford.edu"&gt;mpulloa@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9565362403</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9565362403</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>international news</category></item><item><title>Two Arts Writers/Practitioners to Come to Stanford in 2011-12</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Humanities Center and the &lt;a href="http://arts.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford Institute for Creativity and the Arts (SiCa)&lt;/a&gt; are pleased to announce that two arts writers/practitioners have been chosen to come to Stanford in 2011-12 as part of a jointly sponsored program entering its second year. Nominated by Stanford departments and research centers, the arts writers/practitioners will be on campus for four-week residencies. They will have offices at the Humanities Center and will be affiliated with their nominating unit, the Humanities Center, and SiCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These residencies bring high-profile arts writers/practitioners into the intellectual life of the university, targeting scholars whose arts practice and writing engage with the missions of both the Humanities Center and SiCa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following artists have been selected for the upcoming academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rafael Campo&lt;/strong&gt; is an internationally recognized physician and poet, a leader in medical humanities and the award-winning author of seven books. A recipient of a Guggenheim fellowship as well as a finalist for the National Book Critics Circle Award, he is an associate professor of medicine at Harvard Medical School and the director of the Office for Multicultural Affairs. A prominent figure in the LGBT medical community, Dr. Campo will lead writing workshops for medical and creative writing students during his time on campus. He was nominated by the Arts, Humanities, and Medicine Program at the Stanford Center for Biomedical Ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.K. Raina&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the most distinguished theatre practitioners in India today. He is a graduate of India’s premier theatre institution, the National School of Drama based in New Delhi and his unique talents have been recognized by India’s highest awards, including the B.V. Karanth Award for Lifetime Achievement in Theatre in 2007. One of the few Indian artists who tackles the complex questions of human rights, democracy, and militant terror in the Kashmir valley—his birthplace—his work is informed by his dynamic engagement in secular activism and ranges from Kashmiri folk theatre (working with the Bhand Pather, Kashmiri folk performers) to classical Hindustani and avant-garde cinema. He was nominated by the Centre for South Asia. M.K. Raina will be present on campus in October 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at Stanford, Campo and Raina will offer informal seminars, demonstrations, student workshops, and public lectures and will also be available for consultations with interested faculty and students. For additional information, please contact Marie-Pierre Ulloa, &lt;a href="mailto:mpulloa@stanford.edu"&gt;mpulloa@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee reviewed an unusually strong field of candidates and decided to assist financially in bringing three other nominees to campus: photographer &lt;strong&gt;Rosamund Purcell&lt;/strong&gt;, the author of &lt;em&gt;Landscapes of the Passing Strange: Reflections from Shakespeare&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;strong&gt;Jeff Chang&lt;/strong&gt;, award winning author of &lt;em&gt;Can’t Stop Won’t Stop: A History of the Hip-Hop Generation&lt;/em&gt; (2005); and &lt;strong&gt;Judith Barrington&lt;/strong&gt;, poet and memoirist, most recently published &lt;em&gt;Lost Lands &lt;/em&gt;(2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564593473</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564593473</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>Arts News</category></item><item><title>Center Announces International Visitors for 2011-12</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Humanities Center and the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies (FSI) are pleased to announce that four international scholars have been chosen to come to Stanford in 2011-12 as part of a jointly sponsored international program entering its third year. Nominated by Stanford departments and research centers, the international visitors will be on campus for four-week residencies. They will have offices at the Humanities Center and will be affiliated with their nominating unit, the Humanities Center, and FSI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major purpose of the residencies is to bring high-profile international scholars into the intellectual life of the university, targeting scholars whose research and writing engage with the missions of both the Humanities Center and FSI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following four scholars have been selected for the upcoming academic year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adams Bodomo&lt;/strong&gt; (October-November 2011) is the Chair of the Department of Linguistics in the School of Humanities at the University of Hong Kong and the Director of the University’s African Studies Program. A linguist hailing from Ghana, his primary expertise resides in the structure of West-African languages (Akan, Dagaare) and he has recently undertaken research on African diaspora in Asia, conducted fieldwork on Zhuang, a minority language in China. He was nominated by the Department of Linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mario Carretero&lt;/strong&gt; (January 2012) is a Professor of Psychology at Autonoma University of Madrid, and one of the most prominent leaders studying how young people develop historical consciousness and how they understand history. His work has been at the forefront of the “history wars” since the 1990s over what and who should determine the curriculum on the Spanish-speaking world. Carretero’s research, unlike scholars who explore such issues by dissecting textbooks, is unique in its commitment to fieldwork - conducting interviews with adolescents and observing them in real life situations to understand the dynamics of cultural transmission and resistance. He was nominated by the School of Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catherine Gousseff&lt;/strong&gt; (February 2012) is a world-renowned leading figure in East-Central European history, politics, and society of the twentieth century, as well as of the former Soviet Union. A researcher at the French &lt;em&gt;Centre national de la recherche scientifique&lt;/em&gt; (CNRS), she is currently affiliated with the Marc Bloch Center in Berlin. While at Stanford, she will share insights into her new research project on collective memories of displacements and diaspora politics in the wartime and post-war eras, notably the Polish-Ukrainian population exchange (1944-1950) based on research in Russian, Ukrainian and Polish archives. She was nominated by the Europe Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Laidlaw&lt;/strong&gt; (April 2012) is an anthropologist at Cambridge University. Professor Laidlaw is deeply engaged in fieldwork in Asia, researching the Buddhist ethics of self-cultivation, looking at how the traditional means by which Buddhists practice self-cultivation –asceticism, meditation- are undergoing a massive restructuring. Practices once reserved for male monks are now being adopted by women and laity. James Laidlaw has edited seven books, two of which are on cognitive approaches to religion, exploring them from an ethnographic perspective. He is also an expert on Jainism, a tradition of monastic renunciation like Buddhism. He was nominated by the Department of Anthropology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564688434</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564688434</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>international news</category></item><item><title>Fellows Update Winter 2011</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications, promotions, and awards! Here’s what we’ve heard from you since the fall. Please stay in touch, and if you have news to share, send an email to &lt;a href="mailto:shc-newsletter@stanford.edu"&gt;shc-newsletter@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009-10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARAH LOCHLANN JAIN explored the issue of cancer in “&lt;a href="http://humanexperience.stanford.edu/"&gt;A Special Case: The Young Cancer Patient&lt;/a&gt;” for the &lt;em&gt;Human Experience&lt;/em&gt; series “Thinking Twice.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008-09&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TERRY CASTLE is featured in &lt;em&gt;The Chronicle of Higher Education&lt;/em&gt; article “&lt;a href="http://chronicle.com/article/Terry-Castle-Critical-Outlaw/125650/"&gt;Terry Castle, Critical Outlaw&lt;/a&gt;.” Her recent book &lt;em&gt;The Professor  &lt;/em&gt;was chosen as one of the Top 10 Books of the year by &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/arts/cultureawards/2010/69903/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as well as one of the Favorite Books of 2010 by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/bookforum/status/4224673927663616"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BookForum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; it was also named Editor’s Pick #2 in the top ten books in Gay and Lesbian Studies by &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/feature.html?ie=UTF8&amp;plgroup=1&amp;docId=1000628081"&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONG GUOQING received a promotion to full professorship from Nanjing University. His promotion came on the heels of a number of recent publications: “Local Factionalism in the Cultural Revolution: Nanjing Under Military Control,” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Asian Studies&lt;/em&gt; (June 2011); ”Factions in a Bureaucratic Setting: The Origins of Cultural Revolution Conflict in Nanjing,” &lt;em&gt;China Journal&lt;/em&gt; (January 2011); ”Nanjing’s failed January Revolution of 1967: The Inner Politics of an Aborted Power Seizure,” &lt;em&gt;China Quarterly&lt;/em&gt; (September 2010); and “The First Uprising of the Cultural Revolution at Nanjing University: Dynamics, Nature and Interpretation,” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cold War Studies&lt;/em&gt; (Summer 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006-07&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HANS THOMALLA has won the prestigious Composer’s Prize from the Ernst von Siemens Music Foundation. The prize is a great honor for young composers and is awarded with a cash prize and a composition commission. &lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/intellectual-life/news/former-fellow-hans-thomalla-wins-ernst-von-siemens-composers-prize"&gt;Read more about the prize»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2005-06&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MARGARET COHEN published &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://press.princeton.edu/titles/9320.html"&gt;The Novel and the Sea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Princeton University Press, 2010), a literary history that questions our land-locked assumptions about the novel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002-03&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARNOLD RAMPERSAD received the 2010 National Humanities Medal, bestowed by President Obama during a ceremony at the White House on March 2, 2011. Rampersad was honored for his work as a biographer and literary critic. &lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/intellectual-life/news/former-fellow-arnold-rampersad-awarded-national-humanities-medal"&gt;READ MORE»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001-02&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEBRA SATZ recently published &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://%20http//humanexperience.stanford.edu/publications"&gt;Why Some Things Should Not Be for Sale: The Moral Limits of Markets &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Oxford University Press, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1994-95&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LAWRENCE JACKSON published his second book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://press.princeton.edu/titles/9295.html"&gt;The Indignant Generation: A Narrative History of African American Writers and Critics, 1934-1960&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (Princeton University Press, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1991-92&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAVID HAHN finished composing “TIC*TAC*TOE” for mandolin, guitar, and electronic sound. The piece was commissioned by the German-based MARE Duo and will be included on their next CD, &lt;em&gt;Sound Design&lt;/em&gt;.  He is currently working as sound designer for the Seattle Publc Theatre‚ March 2011 production of &lt;em&gt;The Happy Ones&lt;/em&gt;, a play by Julie Marie Myatt. He also founded the performing ensemble Concert Imaginaire which performs free improvisations and Eastern European folk music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His 4-movement piece for mandolin and guitar, “&lt;a href="http://www.clearnote.net/PassionateIsolation.html"&gt;Passionate Isolation&lt;/a&gt;,” has been published by Clear Note Publications. The piece won the 2003 Composition Prize from the Classical Mandolin Society of America. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1989-90&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICHARD PRICE published a new book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.upenn.edu/pennpress/book/14807.html"&gt;Rainforest Warriors: Human Rights on Trial&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(University of Pennsylvania Press, 2011). Another of his books, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Tooy: History, Memory, and the African American Imagination&lt;/em&gt;(University of Chicago Press, 2008), won the 2008 Victor Turner Prize in Ethnographic Writing, the 2009 Gordon K. and Sybil Lewis Memorial Award for Caribbean Scholarship, and the 2009 Clifford Geertz Prize in the Anthropology of Religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1987-88&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARBARA BABCOCK has a new book out with Stanford University Press titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sup.org/book.cgi?id=1888"&gt;Woman Lawyer: The Trials of Clara Foltz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (2011). The January edition of &lt;a href="http://www.rorotoko.com/"&gt;Rorotoko&lt;/a&gt; featured a fascinating interview with Babcock on Clara Foltz’s life and why today we would call her a “public intellectual.” &lt;a href="http://www.rorotoko.com/index.php/article/barbara_babcock_book_interview_woman_lawyer_trials_clara_foltz/"&gt;READ MORE»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1982-83&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HERBERT LINDENBERGER published &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cambridge.org/aus/catalogue/catalogue.asp?isbn=9780521199896"&gt;Situating Opera: Period, Genre, Reception&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Cambridge University Press, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564629333</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564629333</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>Fellows News</category></item><item><title>International Visitor Thitinan Pongsudhirak Featured on Forum with Michael Krasny</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humanities Center International Visitor Thitinan Pongsudhirak appeared on &lt;em&gt;Forum&lt;/em&gt; with Michael Krasny on March 16, 2010, to discuss the recent political turbulence in Thailand, where the Red-shirted supporters of deposed Thai premier Thaksin Shinawatra took to the streets, clashing with riot police. Krasny and Pongsudirak examine what the current political tensions say about Thailand today, and what they mean for the country tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thitinan Pongsudhirak is professor of international political economy in the Faculty of Political Science at Chulalongkorn University in Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To listen to the conversation, &lt;a href="http://www.kqed.org/epArchive/R201003160931?itemMD5=a7ce92bd0c0571266ff1c8dd9a99c2e5"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9565540174</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9565540174</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><category>international news</category></item><item><title>Former Fellow Hans Thomalla Wins the Ernst von Siemens Composer's Prize</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Geballe fellow and composer Hans Thomalla is to receive one of the three prestigious prizes for young composers awarded by the Ernst von Siemens Music Foundation. The prize is valued at 40,000 euros and is awarded together with a composition commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The award will be presented to Thomalla at a musical ceremony in Munich at the Cuvilliés Theatre on 24 May 2011. The saxophone quartet XASAX will perform his new work for the first time. The board of trustees of the Ernst von Siemens Music Foundation, which includes the composers Wolfgang Rihm and Helmut Lachenmann, sees Thomalla as being one of the most important up-and-coming young composers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hans Thomalla was born in Bonn, Germany in 1975, and studied composition at the Frankfurt Musikhochschule. In 1999 he was appointed first assistant dramaturge, later dramaturge and artistic advisor to the director at the Stuttgart Opera, where he worked on the new productions of Lachenmann’s &lt;em&gt;Mädchen mit den Schwefelhölzern&lt;/em&gt; as well as Schreker’s &lt;em&gt;Gezeichnete&lt;/em&gt; among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2002-2007 he pursued a Doctor of Musical Arts at Stanford University. He was a fellow of the DAAD, the Studienstiftung des deutschen Volkes, and the Stanford Humanities Center during his studies. Hans Thomalla won the Christoph-Delz-Prize in 2006 and the Kranichsteiner Musikpreis in 2004, and he has been a fellow at the MacDowell Colony, and the SWR-Experimentalstudio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His music has been performed at major Festivals, such as Tanglewood, Donaueschingen, Wien Modern, Witten, Ultraschall Berlin, ECLAT-Festival, Takefu, and Steirischer Herbst. In 2005 the Festival d’Automne à Paris presented a portrait of his music in two concerts with the ensemble recherche. The City of Zurich, Switzerland, featured his music in four concerts at the 2008 Contemporary Music Days. In 2008 a Portrait-CD with Hans Thomalla’s chamber music played by the ensemble recherche and Lucas Fels was released on the Wergo Label. Future projects include an Opera Fremd for the main stage of the Stuttgart Opera, a new piece for the Donaueschingen Festival and a string quartet for the Arditti Quartet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hans Thomalla is on the advisory board for the new director of the Darmstadt Summer Courses, and he was on the courses composition faculty in 2010. Since 2007 he has been assistant professor of composition at Northwestern University in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the Ernst von Siemens Music Foundation for more &lt;a href="http://www.evs-musikstiftung.ch/en/composers-grants-in-aid/composers-prize-winners-2011/hans-thomalla/"&gt;information about Hans Thomalla&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564762158</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564762158</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><category>Fellows News</category></item><item><title>Former Fellow Arnold Rampersad Awarded the National Humanities Medal</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqrjeasDNI1qmvxz1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former fellow and Professor Emeritus of English at Stanford Arnold Rampersad has received the  2010 National Humanities Medal. President Obama bestowed the award to Rampersad and 9 other honorees at a White House ceremony on March 2, 2011. After the ceremony, the medalists and their families and friends joined the President and First Lady Michelle Obama for a reception in their honor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rampersad was honored for his work as a biographer and literary critic. His award-winning books have profiled W.E.B. Du Bois, Langston Hughes, Jackie Robinson, and Ralph Ellison. He has also edited critical editions of the works of Richard Wright and Langston Hughes (&lt;a href="http://www.neh.gov/news/archive/2010_Medalists.html#No8"&gt;full profile&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Humanities Medal is the highest government honor given in recognition of outstanding achievements in history, literature, education, and cultural policy. It honors individuals or groups whose work has deepened the country’s understanding of the humanities, broadened our citizens’ engagement with the humanities, or helped preserve and expand Americans’ access to important resources in the humanities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1996, when the first National Humanities Medal was given, 125 individuals have been honored, inclusive of this year’s awardees. Nine organizations also received medals. Previous medalists include Nobel Prize winner Toni Morrison, novelist John Updike, Nobel Peace Prize laureate Elie Wiesel, sociologist Robert Coles, and filmmaker Steven Spielberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2011/03/01/president-obama-award-2010-national-medal-arts-and-national-humanities-m"&gt;the White House press release&lt;/a&gt;. A video and full transcript of the ceremony are also available on &lt;a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/photos-and-video/video/2011/03/02/2010-national-medal-arts-and-national-humanities-medal-ceremony"&gt;the White House website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564795891</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564795891</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><category>Fellows News</category></item><item><title>Authors Tim O'Brien and Tobias Wolff Discuss Writing About Vietnam</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqrjfoi87y1qmvxz1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 24, 2011, award-winning author Tim O’Brien was invited by the Stanford Humanities Center to address the relationship between writing and war at the annual Raymond Fred West Memorial Lecture. O’Brien sat down with fellow veteran and author Tobias Wolff to tackle such perennial questions as, How do you portray the horrors of war? What are the responsibilities of the writer? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coverage of the event has been extensive. For some different perspectives on the conversation, see the &lt;a href="http://stanford.us1.list-manage.com/track/click?u=e19e81c72e023459082e89514&amp;id=8fd50fa58c&amp;e=f6c1817fbe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stanford Report’s&lt;/em&gt; article by Cynthia Haven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://stanford.us1.list-manage1.com/track/click?u=e19e81c72e023459082e89514&amp;id=5d64fa1ee3&amp;e=f6c1817fbe"&gt;Caroline Chen’s article&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://stanford.us1.list-manage.com/track/click?u=e19e81c72e023459082e89514&amp;id=bdbc257701&amp;e=f6c1817fbe"&gt;interview with Tim O’Brien&lt;/a&gt; in the&lt;em&gt; Stanford Daily&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://stanford.us1.list-manage.com/track/click?u=e19e81c72e023459082e89514&amp;id=b80e1c884d&amp;e=f6c1817fbe"&gt;a piece by Christina Farr&lt;/a&gt; on the CISAC news site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was part of a yearlong series on Ethics and War at Stanford University, and was co-sponsored by Creative Writing and the McCoy Family Center for Ethics in Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full video of the conversation between Tim O’Brien and Tobias Wolff on “Writing and War” &lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/intellectual-life/video-podcasts/detail/tim-obrien-conversation-tobias-wolff-writing-and-war"&gt;is now available online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564827317</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564827317</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><category>Events</category></item><item><title>International Visitor Reflects on Thailand's Misrule by Law</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an article for the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, former FSI-Stanford Humanities Center International Visitor Thitinan Pongsudhirak questions Thailand’s return to the rule of law and argues that the judicial and military establishment are skewing the playing field in favor of the ruling party. &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704694004576018852997282210.html"&gt;Read the full article»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thitinan Pongsudhirak is professor of international political economy and director of the Institute of Security and International Studies at Chulalongkorn University in Bangkok. &lt;a href="http://shc.stanford.edu/people/directory/thitinan-pongsudhirak"&gt;Read his full bio»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564872129</link><guid>http://stanfordhumanitiescenter.tumblr.com/post/9564872129</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><category>international news</category></item></channel></rss>
